（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)
（徽标弹出）
(logo popping)
（金属滑动）
(metal sliding)
- 让我们看看如何预处理翻译数据集。
- Let's see how to preprocess a dataset for translation.
这个任务需要将句子用另一种语言
This is a task of well translating a sentence
进行恰当的翻译。
in another language.
本视频将重点介绍当你把句子按照下面的格式组织时
This video will focus on how to preprocess your dataset
如何预处理你的数据集。
once you've managed to put it in the following format.
一列用于输入文本，一列用于目标文本。
One column for input texts and one for the target texts.
以下是我们如何使用 Datasets 库实现此目的
Here is how we can achieve this with the Datasets library
以及用于英语到法语翻译的 KDE4 数据集。
and the KDE4 dataset for English to French translation.
只要你能够让数据按照这样的形式组织，
As long as you manage to have your data look like this,
就应该可以按照相同的步骤操作。
you should be able to follow the same steps.
这一次，我们对于某些类的标签不是整数
For once, our labels are not integers
而是纯文本。
corresponding to some classes, but plain texts.
因此，我们需要将它们词元化，就像我们的输入一样。
We will thus need to tokenize them, like our inputs.
虽然那里有一个陷阱，
There is a trap there though,
好像你按照输入那样词元化你的目标，
as if you tokenize your targets like your inputs,
就会遇到一个问题。
you will hit a problem.
即使你不会说法语，你也可能会注意到
Even if you don't speak French, you might notice
目标词元化后出现了一些奇怪的东西。
some weird things in the tokenization of the targets.
大多数单词都被处理为几个子词元，
Most of the words are tokenized in several subtokens,
而 fish，文本中唯一的英语单词，
while fish, one of the only English word,
被词元化为一个单独的词。
is tokenized as a single word.
那是因为我们的输入已经按照英语进行词元化。
That's because our inputs have been tokenized as English.
由于我们的模型涉及两种语言，
Since our model knows two languages,
你必须在词元化目标时提示它
you have to warn it when tokenizing the targets
从而切换到法语模式。
so it switches in French mode.
这是通过 as_target_tokenizer 上下文管理器完成的。
This is done with the as_target_tokenizer context manager.
你可以看到它如何导致更紧凑的词元化。
You can see how it results in a more compact tokenization.
处理整个数据集
Processing the whole dataset
然后配合 map 函数使用非常简单。
is then super easy with the map function.
你可以为输入和目标输出
You can pick different maximum lengths
选择不同的最大长度，
for the inputs and targets,
并通过设置 padding=max_length
and choose to pad at this stage to that maximum length
在此阶段填充到最大长度。
by setting padding=max_length.
由于还需要再多一步
Here we'll show you to pad dynamically
所以这里我们将向你展示动态填充。
as it requires one more step.
你的输入和目标结果
Your inputs and targets
都是各种长度的句子。
are all sentences of various lengths.
由于输入和目标结果的最大长度可能会不同，
We will pad the inputs and targets separately,
我们将分别填充输入
as the maximum lengths of the inputs and targets
和目标结果。
might be different.
然后我们用 pad token 填充输入
Then we pad the inputs with the pad token
以及索引为 -100 的目标输出
and the targets with the -100 index
确保它们不被包含在
to make sure they're not taken into account
损失计算中。
in the loss computation.
一旦完成上述操作，
Once this is done,
批处理输入和目标输出变得超级容易。
batching inputs and targets become super easy.
Transformers 库为我们提供了数据整理器
The Transformers library provides us with data collator
自动完成这一切。
to do this all automatically.
之后你可以在你的 Keras 模型上使用 model.fit () 之前
You can then pass it to the Trainer with your datasets
将它与你的数据集一起传递给 Trainer
or use it in the to_tf_dataset method
或者在 to_tf_dataset 方法中使用它。
before using model.fit () on your Keras model.
（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)